emblibrary.com 2018-04-03

# Machine Embroidery Designs at Embroidery Library! - Privacy Policy

## Privacy Statement for Embroidery Library Inc.  
This page was last edited on 05/19/2017

> This privacy statement describes how [Embroidery Library Inc.](http://www.emblibrary.com/) collects and uses the personal information you provide on our Web site: www.emblibrary.com. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request. 
> 
> Embroidery Library Inc. has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy.   
>  The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website: [http://www.emblibrary.com](http://www.emblibrary.com/). 
> 
> **Log Files**
> 
> As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you.   
> We do this to improve services we offer you and to gather analytics to enhance the site functionality.  
> 
> **Tracking Technologies**
> 
> We, Embroidery Library, and our service providers, PayPal or Credit Card processor,   
>  use technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags, and scripts, to analyze trends, administer the website, tracking users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual and aggregated basis.
> 
> We use cookies for our shopping cart, to remember users’ settings (e.g. language preference), and for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level by using the local browser tools. If you reject cookies, you may still use our website, but your ability to use some features or areas of our website may be limited.
> 
> **Registration**
> 
> Our site's registration form requires users to give us contact information (such as their name and email address and password).   
>  The registration form also collects your address.  This information is completely optional and is used to populate the billing address in the Purchase form.    
>  The customer's contact information is used to contact the customer if necessary.
> 
> Reasons for email originating from the Embroidery Library include;   
> Issues with an order that the customer has placed.   
> Updates to our privacy statement that include any changes with how we use your information.   
> We do not send out any junk email.    
> Emails are sent on occasion with updates about the Embroidery Library.
> 
> You do have an option to not receive the updates.    
> To unsubscribe from our email updates please send an email to [stitch@emblibrary.com](mailto:stitch@emblibrary.com) or reply to one of our emails with the subject 'Unsubscribe'.  
>  This information is not used in any other way and is 
> 
> _never_
> 
> shared with any other companies. 
> 
>  **Information Sharing**
> 
> We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement.   
> 
> 
> **Service Provider**
> 
> We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities   
>  such as order payment via PayPal or credit card. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.   
> 
> 
> **Links**
> 
> This site contains links to other sites. **Embroidery Library** is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. As privacy practices may be different at other sites please review each site's privacy statement.  
> 
> 
> **Social Media Widgets**
> 
> Our website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button, and Widgets, such as the Share This button or interactive mini-programs that run on our website. These Features may collect your Internet protocol address, which page you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website.   
> Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it. 
> 
> **Contests**
> 
> Occasionally the Embroidery Library sponsors contests held by other sites.  The Embroidery Library does not ask for any additional information to enter a contest.  If you are asked for any information please be aware that this information is being requested from the originator of the contest.  
>  For any questions about privacy issues regarding information being collected by the contest owner please refer to their privacy statement. 
> 
> **Orders**
> 
> Our site uses an order form for customers to request products. We collect visitor's billing and financial information (such as their account or credit card numbers). Financial information that is collected is used only to bill the user for products and services.    
> This information is used only for that purpose and is _never_ shared with any other person or company.   
> We do use a secure third party to process credit cards.  
>  If you choose to use PayPal to finalize and pay for your order, you will provide your credit card number, directly to PayPal.  
>  [PayPal's Privacy Statement](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) will apply to the information you provide on the PayPal website.  
>  We don't store credit card information, other than that required by the Credit Card companies, for any use other than processing the credit card transactions.
> 
> If a customer purchases a gift certificate through our site, we will ask customers for the name and email address of the intended recipient.  This information is used to send an email to the recipient of the certificate notifying them of the gift.
> 
> Embroidery Library, Inc. stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. 
> 
> Our store maintains a list of receipts or Order History for each customer.  This information is accessible by logging in to the store and then clicking on the Order History link located in the right margin of the Lobby page or at the top of your Basket page. This information is for your convenience.  It is not available to anyone else.  
>  Your credit card information is not stored in your Order History. 
> 
> **Newsletter**
> 
> The Embroidery Library sends out newsletters to customers.    
>  If you wish to unsubscribe from this newsletter please email us at [ stitch@emblibrary.com](mailto:stitch@emblibrary.com) or reply to a newsletter with 'Unsubscribe' as the subject. 
> 
> **Security**
> 
> We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once it is received. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at [stitch@emblibrary.com.](mailto:stitch@emblibrary.com)
> 
> **Correct/Update**
> 
> Upon request Embroidery Library, Inc. will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. This site gives users the following options for changing, deleting, or modifying information previously provided. 
> 
>   1. You may email [stitch@emblibrary.com](mailto:stitch@emblibrary.com)
>   2. Or, visit [http://www.emblibrary.com](https://www.emblibrary.com/el/profile/general.aspx), after you have logged into the store, click on the 'My Profile' link located in the upper right margin of our web pages.
>   3. To remove your information from our database, Please send an email to [stitch@emblibrary.com](mailto:stitch@emblibrary.com) asking that your information be removed from our database.  Please note, by completely removing your information from our database all record of your orders with us will also be removed. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.
> 

> 
> **Data Retention**
> 
> We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [stitch@emblibrary.com](mailto:stitch@emblibrary.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.   
> Please note, by completely removing your information from our database all record of your orders with us will also be removed. 
> 
> **Updates**
> 
> We will notify you of material changes to our privacy statement with a notice on our Home page [http://www.emblibrary.com](http://www.emblibrary.com/).    
>  If we ever make material changes to the way we handle your personal information you will be contacted by email in advance.    
>  At that time if you wish to remove any information that is stored with us you may do so.  The opt-out instructions will be in the posted changes notice.
> 
> **Contacting the Web Site**
> 
> If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact: Embroidery Library Inc. 5000 Chesire Pkwy North Ste #3 Minneapolis, MN 55446 stitch@emblibrary.com 763-509-3320
> 
> ## Legal Disclaimer
> 
> Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, when required by law such as to comply with a subpoena, bankruptcy proceedings, or similar legal process when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request. If Embroidery Library, Inc. is involved in a merger, acquistion, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.
